--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.tv
影片压制:梦幻  字幕制作:梦幻  招募Q群:324446465
片名：这个杀手不太冷
Allora, come stai, Leone?
最近怎么样 里昂
Bene.
挺好的
Okay, okay.Let's talk business.
好吧 我们来谈点正经事儿
This fat bastard is moving in
这个死胖子插手了
on Morizio's business.
莫里奇奥的买卖
You know Morizio is a reasonable guy.
你知道莫里奇奥是讲道理的
He just wants a little conversation.
他只想谈谈
But this guy, he don't wanna hear about it.
但这家伙 他不想听
Maybe he'll listen to you.
或许他会听你的
He comes to town every Tuesday.
他每周二来镇上
Are you free Tuesday?
你周二有空吗
Yeah, I'm free Tuesday.
嗯 有空
Nice to see you again, Mr. Jones.
真高兴再见到你 琼斯先生
Remember, neatness counts.You got one half hour.
记住 办得利落点 给你半小时
One hour.
一小时
Yea... What?
怎么了
It's Tonto, downstairs.
我是楼下的唐托
There's a guy wants to talk to you.
这儿有个人想跟你谈谈
What's he look like?
他长什么样
Serious.
蛮严肃的
Tell him I'm coming up.
告诉他我要上来了
He's coming up.
他要上来了
Somebody's coming up. Somebody serious.
有人来了 来者不善
Mickey,
米基
open your eyes. We got company.
眼睛擦亮点 有人来砸场儿了
We got company.
有人来砸场儿了
Come on.
来吧
Stop! Stop, man!
住手 快住手
Tonto.
唐托
Tell the driver to wait for us out back, and hurry up.
叫在外面等我们的司机回来 赶紧的
Hey sweetie, what's going on?
亲爱哒 肿么啦
Don't worry, baby.It's cool. Take a nap.
宝贝 别担心 没事儿 你再歇会儿吧
Oh, my God.
天哪
Those fuckers blocked both the exits.
这些混蛋把两个出口都堵了
Check the terrace!
去检查阳台
911 emergency.
这里是911紧急热线
I need help. Somebody's trying to kill me.
救命 有人要杀我
Alright. Just stay on the line. I'll just be off a moment.
请别挂机 马上帮您转接
Sir, I'm gonna connect you with an officer.
先生 即将为您接通一个警官
Detective Jefferson. May I help you?
我是杰弗逊警探 有什么需要帮助的吗
I'll call you back.
待会儿再打给你
Relax, man.
兄弟 放松点
I got half of Bolivia sitting in them suitcases.
那边手提箱里的毒品可以买下半个玻利维亚
Hasn't even been cut yet.
还没勾兑过
Go ahead, take it.It's yours.
去吧 拿走吧 都归你
Dial this number.
拨这个号码
I'll talk to you later, sweetie, okay?
亲爱的 我们回头再约哈
Bye.
拜拜
Hello?
你好
It's Morizio. Remember me?
我是莫里奇奥 还记得我吗
I see you're back in town.
我知道你回镇上了
Yeah. I mean, no.Just for today.
嗯 哦不 我的意思是 就待今天一天
So it's safe to say today's your last day in town...
那不妨说今天也是你在镇上的最后一天
and we'll never see your fat fucking face again.
我们再也不用看到你那张肥猪脸了
Yeah. Right.
对对对
Let me speak to our mutual friend.
让我跟咱们共同的朋友说两句
He wants to talk to you.
他要你接电话
Yeah.
嗯
Make sure he understands, and let him go.
确保他明白我的意思 然后让他滚
Do you understand?
你明白了吗
So say it.
说出来
I understand.
我明白了
Good.
很好
Jesus.
苍天啊
Two milk as usual?
照例两盒牛奶吗
Hi
嗨
Why did you hide the cigarette?
你为什么把烟藏起来
This building's full of rats.
楼里到处是耗子
I didn't want my old man to find out.
我可不想我家老头儿发现
Got enough problems.
麻烦够多了
What happened?
怎么弄的
I fell off my bike.
骑自行车摔的
Don't tell my dad about the cigarette, okay?
不要告诉我爸香烟的事儿 好吗
- Why are you doing this to us? - I don't know...
- 你为什么这么对我们 - 我真的不知道
People got memory problems these days.
现在人都很健忘的
It must be the sun.
一定是太阳把脑子烧坏了
Know when to come out of the sun.
少晒点太阳 好好想想
I don't know how it happened.
我不知道怎么会发生这种事
What's my job? I'm just a holder.
我只负责保管
I hold the stuff you give to me.
保管你们给我的东西
I don't look at it or touch it.
不看 不碰
I don't know how to cut it.
我甚至不知道怎么稀释
Try to follow me.
听着
In June, we gave you the dope.
我们六月份给你这些毒品
It tests 100 percent pure.
当时纯度还是百分之百
Now it's July, we pick up the dope,
现在七月了 我们再来拿
and it tests 90 percent pure.
测出来纯度只有百分之九十
Somewhere between June and July,
六月到七月中的某个时间
ten percent turned to cut!
百分之十的纯度不见了
I don't know. It's none of my business.
我不知道 不关我的事
You give me the stuff, I hold it.
你给了我 我就只负责保管
That's all I know.
我就知道这么多
Look, you know, I'm trying to help you out here...
好吧 你看 我在试图拉你出苦海
but if you're gonna be a hard-ass about it...
但你要是再这么嘴硬
I gotta disturb him.
我就要去打扰他了
Let me tell you.
告诉你
When he's into his music,
他沉浸在音乐中的时候
he hates being disturbed.
最恨被人打扰了
I'm telling you the truth.
我说的都是实话
I hope so,
但愿如此
because he's got a talent for sniffin' out a lie.
因为他有嗅出谎言的天赋
It's scary.It's almost like a sixth sense.
很吓人的 就像是第六感
Are you gonna
你是要
change your tune
改变主意
or I gotta bust into his?
还是要我去麻烦他呢
I'm telling you the truth.
我说的就是实话
All right.
好吧
Stan.
史丹
I'm sorry. He said he didn't cut the dope.
对不起 他说他没稀释毒品
Oh
哦
Of course he didn't.
他当然没有
Just do me a favor.Find out who did by tomorrow.
帮我个忙 明天查出来是谁做的
Noon.
正午之前
Malky, wait.
马尔奇 等等
I didn't cut your shit.Find out yourself!
我又没做 你自己查去吧
What are you doin' out here?
你在这儿干嘛
Get inside and do your homework.
进去做你的作业
I did it already.
我做完了
Oh yeah? Get inside and help your sister
是吗 那滚进去帮你姐姐
clean up the goddamn house!
打扫下该死的屋子
And stop smoking cigarettes!
不许再抽烟
Time's up. My turn.
时间到了 该我看了
Change the channel, and I'll smash your face.
你要是敢换台 我就撕碎你的脸
Sorry, sweetheart.
抱歉 亲爱的
Oh Sweetie
早 小宝贝儿
Hi, honey, you two.
嗨 亲爱的 好孩子
Sweetheart, turn that down.
宝贝 把声音调低点
Mama's got a headache.
妈妈头疼死了
She took my turn.
她占了我的时间
She wants to watch goddamn cartoons!
她要看傻X的动画片
It wouldn't hurt her to move her ass.
运动下她屁股又不会死
I'm not the one with a fat ass around here.
我又不是屁股肥的那一个
Can someone who's doing nothing all day
那个整天除了看动画片
but watching cartoons...
屁事不做的人
move a little ass and go get some food?
能动下她的小屁屁去弄点吃的吗
I dare you to say that again.
有本事再说一遍
Margie, I think I screwed up.
玛姬 我好像搞砸了
It wouldn't be the first time.
反正也不是第一次了
You always come up with somethin', right?
你总是惹出些麻烦事儿 是吧
I think I went too far this time.
我觉得这次越线了
You're goin' too far right now.
你现在才叫越线
I'm gonna be late for work.
我上班要迟到了
How about workin' at home today?
不如今天在家工作吧
Now it's my turn!
[动画]现在轮到我了
Shit! She's gonna hit me! Daddy!
该死 她要打我 爸
Shit! Shut the goddamn door!
草 把门关上
Fuckin' bitch.
小贱人
Can somebody answer the phone?
谁接下电话
I'm busy!
我忙着呢
Hello?
喂
This is Marguerite McCallister...
我是玛格丽特·麦卡利斯特
headmistress at the Spencer School in Wildwood, NewJersey.
新泽西 威尔伍德市 斯宾瑟学校的校长
Is Mr. Or Mrs. Lando home?
兰多先生或女士在家吗
Yes, this is she.
在 我就是
Mrs. Lando, when your husband enrolled Mathilda at Spencer...
兰多女士 当您丈夫在斯宾瑟为玛蒂尔达注册时
he told us she had "Problems."
他告诉我们她有点"问题"
As you know, we pride ourselves on
正如您所知 我们致力于
turning troubled girls into healthy, productive young women.
将问题少女们培养成健康 有成就的年轻女性
But if they are not here, there is very little we can do.
但是如果她们人都不在这 我们能做的就非常少了
Mathilda left school without permission nearly two weeks ago.
大约两个星期前 玛蒂尔达未经允许离开了学校
I know your husband paid tuition in advance for a year...
我知道您的丈夫预付了一年学费
but if you will refer to the page 20
但是如果您去查阅
in the rules and regulations manual we sent you...
我们寄给您的学生守则第20页
you will see that unless there is a valid excuse
您就会发现 长期缺席者
for prolonged absence your tuition will be forfeit.
除非有正当理由 学费将不会退回
She's dead.
她死了
Tell that fuckin' kid to do a little work around here!
叫那混蛋小孩来做点儿事
Clean up! I'm tired of this fuckin' mess.
打扫干净 我真是受够了这堆垃圾
Hurry up!
快点
电影片段出自歌舞天王吉恩·凯利的《It's Always Fair Weather》
歌曲名为《I Like Myself》
∮Why am I feeling, when things could look black∮
为什么当一切看起来不算乐观的时候
∮That nothing could possibly go wrong∮
我却觉得生活依旧美好
∮This has been a most unusual day∮
这已经成为最特别的一天
∮Love has made me see things in a different way∮
爱让我们用不同的角度看待人和事
Is life always this hard,
生活总是这么艰难吗
or is it just when you're a kid?
还是只有童年时才会这样
Always like this.
总是如此
Keep it.
留着吧
Hey, I'm going grocery shopping. You want some milk?
我要去小卖铺买点东西 你想要点牛奶吗
One quart or two? It's two, right?
要一瓶还是两瓶 是两瓶 对吗
I like these calm little moments before the storm.
我真喜欢这暴风雨前短暂的平静
路德维希·凡·贝多芬：德国著名的音乐家 维也纳古典乐派代表人物之一
It reminds me of Beethoven.
这让我想到了贝多芬
Can you hear it?
你能听到吗
It's like when you put your head to the grass...
就像当你附耳到草丛中
you can hear it growin'.You can hear the insects.
你可以听到它们生长 听到昆虫爬动
Do you like Beethoven?
你喜欢贝多芬吗
Couldn't really say.
不算喜欢
I'm gonna play you some.
我来给你演奏一段
Daddy!
爸爸
You better stay here.
你最好待在这儿
Daddy! Daddy!
爸爸 爸
背景音乐为艾瑞克·塞拉的原创音乐《Noon》 并非贝多芬的交响乐作品
We said noon.
我们说好了正午
I've got one minute past.
但是已经过了一分钟了
You don't like Beethoven.
你不喜欢贝多芬
You don't know what you're missing.
你不知道你错过了什么
Overtures like that get my juices flowing.
那样的前奏就能让我热血沸腾
So powerful.
充满能量
But after his openings, to be honest...
但是前奏过后 说真的
he does tend to get a little fucking boring.
就开始有点太他妈无聊了
That's why I stopped!
所以我停下了
Toss the apartment.
彻查这间屋子
沃尔夫冈·阿玛多伊斯·莫扎特：欧洲著名古典主义音乐作曲家
You're a Mozart fan. I love him too.
你是莫扎特的粉丝 我也喜欢他
I love Mozart!
我超爱莫扎特的
He was Austrian, you know.
他是奥地利人
But for this kind of work, he's a little bit light.
但是做这种工作 他有点太轻柔了
So I tend to go for the heavier guys.
所以我选了些更激烈的
Cool.
不错诶
Dude, what the fuck are you doing?
该死的 你在干什么
Man, keep your bombacut mouth shut.
闭上你的臭嘴
约翰内斯·勃拉姆斯：德国古典主义最后的作曲家 浪漫主义中期作曲家
Check out Brahms. He's good too.
你可以试试勃拉姆斯 他也不错
What the fuck do you know about music?
你他妈懂什么音乐
Man, knock it off!
伙计 消停点
You check the mattress?
你查了床垫吗
Nope.
没有
- Oh! Fuck! - He's dead.
- 噢 该死 - 他已经死了
Stan
史丹
Jesus. Look what you did.
天 看你做了什么
Stan, you all right?
史丹 你还好吗
Look what you did.
你看你做了什么
Hey, Stan, Stan, what are you doin'?
嘿 史丹 你在做什么
What are you doin'. He's dead!
你在做什么 他已经死了
But he ruined my suit.
但是他毁了我的西装
Yeah, I know, but he's dead.
我知道 但是他已经死了
He's a piece of meat. Forget about it. Calm down.
他现在就是一滩肉 别想了 冷静点
I'm calm.
我很冷静
- Stay there, OK? - OK
- 在这待着 成吗 - 好的
Benny!
本尼
Jesus fuckin' Christ, Benny!
我的天 本尼
It's Malky and Stan!
我们是马尔奇和史丹
Take it easy, all right?Come on.
放轻松 好吗 来
Benny!
本尼
Come on, let's get a cigarette. All right?
来 去抽根烟 好吗
Benny, we're comin' out!
本尼 我们要过来了
Benny, don't fire!
本尼 别开枪
Get in there!Jesus fuckin' Christ, Benny!
进去 我的天 本尼
You wear somethin' new and... Got a light?
你穿了新衣服 有火吗
Take it easy.
放轻松
What's happening out there?
外面发生什么了
It's all right, ma'am. D.E.A. Police.
没什么 夫人 我们是缉毒组的
Leave that poor family alone.
放过那可怜的一家吧
Everything's all right. Just calm down
一切都好着呢 只要你冷静下来
I am calm. I'm calm.
我很冷静 我超冷静的
Why don't you leave them alone?
你们为什么不能放过他们呢
He said go back inside.
他说了 回你屋去
Stan, I think it's better if we go inside.
史丹 我觉得我们还是进去比较好
Benny, turn that kitchen upside down! Find that shit!
本尼 把厨房掀了也要给我找出那些东西来
Willy Blood, look what you did!
威利·布拉德 看看你都做了什么
You killed a 4-year-old kid!
你杀了一个4岁小孩
Did you really have to do that?
有必要吗
Please open the door.
求你开开门
Please
拜托
求你了
Benny, there are three kids here.
本尼 他们家有三个小孩
I think Stan killed this girl.
我觉得史丹杀了这个女孩
Willy, that asshole, shot the little boy.
混蛋威利 杀了这个小男孩
The third one's missing. Find her.
第三个不见了 找到她
Shit. We missed the little girl, man.
该死 我们丢了那个小女孩
I'm gonna find the fuckin' super in this goddamn building.
为了找这小混球我要翻遍这栋楼了
- Don't you recognize me - Me, Repugnus, know you
- 你不认识我了吗 - 我暴乱兽 知道你
Yo! I found it!
哟 我找到了
Bingo!
棒
Stan, they found it
史丹 他们找到了
I know.
我知道
There it is.
就是这个
There's cops outside. We better go.
警察来了 我们最好撤
It's the cops outside. We better go. You stay here.
警察来了 我们最好撤 你留这
What do you want me tell them?
你想我怎么跟他们说
Tell them...
告诉他们
we were doing our job.
我们是执行公务
What's your name?
你叫什么名字
Mathilda
玛蒂尔达
Sorry about your father.
关于你爸爸 我很抱歉
If somebody didn't do it one day or another,
如果他们不杀他
I would have probably done it myself.
说不定哪天我自己就动手了
Your mother, she...
你妈妈 她
She's not my mother.
她不是我妈妈
My sister wanted to lose some weight anyway.
我姐姐一天到晚就想着减肥
Bet she never looked better.
但是她从没瘦下来过
She's not even my real sister.
她甚至不是我亲姐
Just a half sister.
只有一半是
Not a good half at that.
还不是好的那一半
If you couldn't stand them, why are you crying?
如果你不喜欢他们 你哭什么
Because they killed my brother.
因为他们杀了我的弟弟
What the hell did he do? He was four years old.
他到底做错了什么 他才4岁
He never used to cry.
他以前从来不哭
He just used to sit next to me and cuddle.
他只会坐在我旁边 靠着我
I was more of a mother to him
比起那头臭母猪
than that goddamned pig ever was.
我更像他的妈妈
Don't talk like that about pigs.
不要这样说猪
They're usually nicer than people.
它们通常比人好
But they smell like shit.
但它们闻起来臭死了
Not true.
不对
As a matter of fact, right now
事实上 现在
I have one in my kitchen that's very clean...it smells very nice.
我厨房里就有一头非常干净的 闻起来也很香的猪
You don't have a pig in your kitchen.
你厨房里没有猪
Yes, I do.
我有
I was just in there, and I didn't see any goddamned pig.
我刚刚就在那 没有看见什么见鬼的猪
Don't move. I'll get him.
别动 我去找它
Piggy, piggy where are you?
小猪 小猪 你在哪儿
There you are.
原来在这儿
Hi, Mathilda.
嗨 玛蒂尔达
Hi, piggy.
嗨 小猪
How are you today?
今天过得好吗
I've seen better days.
并不好
What's your name?
你叫什么名字
Leon.
里昂
Cute name.
名字真可爱
You have anyone to go to,
你有其他人可以求助
any family anyplace else?
其他家庭或者地方可去吗
I'm gonna get some more milk.
我还得去拿点牛奶
Holy shit.
我的天啊
Don't touch that, please.
别碰那个 拜托
Leon, what exactly do you do for a living?
里昂 你究竟是做什么工作的
Cleaner.
清道夫
You mean you're a hit man?
意思是 你是职业杀手
Yeah.
嗯
Cool.
酷
Do you clean anyone?
无论谁都清除吗
No women, no kids. That's the rules.
不杀女人和小孩儿 这是原则
How much would it cost to hire someone to get those dirtbags...
雇人杀掉那些杀了我弟弟的人渣
who killed my brother?
要花多少钱
Five grand a head.
一个人头五千美金
How about this.I work for you...
这样好不好 我为你工作
and in exchange, you teach me how to clean?
作为交换 你教我怎么杀人
What do you think?
你觉得怎么样
I'll clean your place. I'll do the shopping.
我给你打扫屋子 出门采购
I'll even wash your clothes.
我还会给你洗衣服
Is it a deal?
干不干
No, it's not a deal.
不 这买卖我不干
What do you want me to do? I've got no place to go.
那你让我怎么办 我没地方可去了
You've had a rough day today.
你经历了可怕的一天
Go to sleep, and we'll see tomorrow,OK?
去睡一觉 我们明天再商量 好吗
You've been really great with me, Leon...
你对我真好 里昂
and it's not always like that.
没人对我这么好过
You know?
你知道吗
Good night.
晚安
You sleep well?
睡得好吗
Good. After breakfast you gotta take off.
好 吃过早饭之后你就得走了
Where to?
去哪里
Not my problem.
和我无关
Read it.
读这个
You don't know how to read.
你不识字
I'm learning, but I've had a lot of work lately...
我正在学 但是最近工作太忙
so I'm a little behind.What's it say?
所以学得有点慢 上面说了什么？
I've decided what to do with my life.
我已经决定这辈子要做什么了
I wanna be a cleaner.
我要做一名清道夫
You wanna be a cleaner. Here.Take it.
你想做一名清道夫 给 拿着
It's a good - bye gift. Go clean,
给你的送别礼 去杀人吧
but not with me. I work alone. Understand? Alone.
但是别和我一起 我单独行动 明白吗 单独
邦妮·派克和克莱德·巴罗：电影《雌雄大盗》主人公
Bonnie and Clyde didn't work alone.
邦妮和克莱德不会单独行动
塞尔玛和路易斯：电影《末路狂花》主人公 因在旅行中意外杀人而逃亡
Thelma and Louise didn't work alone. And they were the best.
塞尔玛和路易斯不会单独行动 而且 她们最厉害
Mathilda, why are you doing this to me?
玛蒂尔达 你为什么要这么对我
I've been nothing but nice to you.
我一直对你挺好的
I even saved your life yesterday, right outside the door.
甚至昨天还救了你一命 就在门外面
Right. So now you're responsible for it.
没错 所以现在你就要为此负责
If you saved my life, you must've saved it for a good reason.
你既然救了我 你肯定有救的理由
If you throw me out now,
如果你现在丢下我
I take it you never opened your door
那就相当于你从没开过门
like you let me die right there in front of it.
那时就已让我死在了你门口
But you did open it.
但是 你开了门
So...
所以
If you don't help me, I'll die tonight. I can feel it.
如果你不帮我 今晚我就会死 我能预知到
I don't wanna die tonight.
今晚我还不想死
You're just a little girl, So
你还只是个小女孩 所以
Don't take it badly, but I don't think you could do it.
别难过 但我不觉得你能当个杀手
I'm sorry.
对不起
How's that?
怎么样
Mathilda, don't you ever do that again or I'll break your head.
玛蒂尔达 你要是再敢那么做 我就打爆你的头
- You got that? - Okay.
- 明白了吗 - 好的
I don't work like that. It's not professional.
我不是那样工作的 那不专业
There is rules.
要有原则
Okay.
好的
And stop saying "Okay" All the time OK?
不要总是说"好的"了 懂吗
Okay.
好的
Good.
很好
You expect to use that in this hotel?
你打算在旅馆里拉小提琴吗
Mister, I have to use it...
先生 我必须要拉 因为
茱莉亚音乐学院：美国著名音乐学院 为8至18岁艺术天才提供系统专业的音乐教育
because I have an audition at Juilliard next month
因为 下个月我在茱莉亚音乐学院有一场试演
and I have to practice.
所以 我必须要练习
Okay, but not after 10:00.
好吧 不过不能在十点之后
Okay, I promise.
好的 我保证
All right.I'll put you at the end of the hall...
好吧 我会把你们安排在走廊尽头
so that you don't disturb anyone.
这样就不会打扰到别人了
Fill those out, please.
请您填了这些表格
Daddy,
爸爸
can I please fill them out?
可以让我填表格吗
You know how I like to check in to hotels.
你知道我很喜欢登记入住信息
Thanks, Pop. I'll bring these back in a minute.
谢谢爸爸 我很快会把表格拿回来
The fourth floor!
在四楼
Thanks, mister!
谢谢您 先生
You're lucky to have a little girl
你很幸运 有一个
that's interested in things.
对一切都感兴趣的女儿
I have a kid, 17, does nothing all day long.
我有个孩子 17岁 整天无所事事
Can I leave my plant here
我能把植物留在这儿
while I take my stuff upstairs?
上楼放行李吗
Of course.
当然
I'm putting in a name of a girl in my class who makes me sick.
我填的是班里一个我讨厌的女生的名字
If things get hot, she'll take the heat.
这样出了麻烦 就由她来担着
There. Finished.
给你 填完了
How old are you?
你多大了
Eighteen.
十八
Eighteen?
Want to see my license?
要看看我的身份证吗
No. You just look a little younger.
不用 只是你看上去要小一点
Thanks.
谢谢
Leon, I want you to teach me how to be like you.
里昂 我想让你教我怎么变得和你一样
- I want to be strong and smart like you. - Mathilda
- 我想像你一样 强大又聪明 - 玛蒂尔达
I know I'm not strong enough yet...
我知道自己现在还不够强大
but I could learn the basics, the theory.
但是我可以先打基础 从理论学起
What do you think? Just the theory.
你觉得呢 只是理论
I need this, Leon.I need time to get my head together.
我需要这么做 里昂 我需要时间稳定情绪
Yeah, and I need...
好吧 而我需要
a drink.
喝一杯
Don't move. I'll go get one.
别动 我去给你拿
When you told me to get this baby out for you...
听到你说让我拿这个玩具给你的时候
I thought my hearin' was goin'.
我还以为自己的耳朵出问题了
I says to myself, " Leon's a pro.
我告诉自己 里昂是专业的
Nobody uses that except beginners."
只有菜鸟才用这东西
I like to stay in shape.
我想要保持状态
Sure.
没错
Always stay on top of it.It's like me.
永远掌控一切 和我一样
I gotta know where everything is all the time.
任何时刻我都要知道所有东西在哪里
That's why I never leave this place, except to go from here to there.
这就是为什么我从来没离开过这里 除了走来走去
Change ain't good, Leon. You know?
改变不是件好事 里昂 你懂吗
Yeah.
嗯
Check it.
检查一下吧
Make sure it's the right thing.
确认这就是你要的
I trust you.
我相信你
One thing's got nothin' to do with the other.
一码是一码 事情要分开算
Remember that.
记住这一点
I will.
我会的
The rifle is the first weapon you learn how to use...
来复枪是你要学习的第一件武器
because it lets you keep your distance from the client.
因为它能让你和目标保持距离
The closer you get to being a pro...
当你越来越专业时
the closer you can get to the client.
你离目标也就越来越近
The knife, for example,
拿刀来举个例子
is the last thing you learn.
刀是你要学习的最后一件武器
Okay?
明白吗
Okay.
好的
Position.
找位置
No.
不对
Never take it off until the last minute.
不到最后一刻 别把镜盖拿下来
It reflects light.
它(瞄准镜)会反射光线
They can see you coming from a mile away.
他们在一英里外都能看到你来了
And always dress down.
还有 记得永远穿着低调
Never brighter than the floor, okay?
比地板还要暗淡 明白吗
Okay.
好的
Let's practice now. It's the best way to learn.
现在我们来练习 这是学习的最好办法了
Who should I hit?
我该射谁呢
Whoever.
谁都行
I'll be with you in a second.
我一会就来
Give me a few minutes.
等我一下
Thank you.
谢谢
You guys get lost. I don't want to see you.
你们怎么就不懂呢 我不要看见你们
This has to look natural.
看上去得自然
No women, no kids. Right?
不杀女人和小孩儿 对吗
Right.
对
Jogger in the yellow and orange?
那个穿橙黄相间外套 在慢跑的人怎么样
Okay.
可以
Keep calm.
保持冷静
Don't take your eyes off him.
视线不要离开目标
Breathe easy.
放慢呼吸
Watch his movement.
观察他的动作
Pretend you're running with him.
假装你跟他一起在跑
Try to feel his next movement.
试着感受他的下一个动作
Take a deep breath. Hold it.
深呼吸 屏息
Now.
开枪
I'm all right. I'm fine.
我没事 我很好
Get down!
趴下
One shot. Not bad, huh?
一击命中 不错吧
Can we try with real bullets now?
现在能用真子弹了吗
Not today. Let's pack up.
今天不行 收工
Like that.
就像这样
No, thanks.
不用 谢了
No discussion.
没得商量
"It seemed to Socrates..."
苏格拉底似乎…
I'll do it.
我来吧
Leon, all we do is work.
里昂 我们整天都在工作
We need a break. Let's play a game.
休息一下 来玩个游戏吧
What kind of game?
什么游戏
I have this great game.
我有个超棒的游戏
It makes you think and helps your memory.
有助于思考和记忆
It's exactly what you need.
正是你所需要的
Okay.
好吧
Who is it?
我是谁
歌手麦当娜1984年发行的经典曲目 《Like A Virgin》
I don't know.
不知道
1962年 玛丽莲·梦露为即将迎来45岁生日的肯尼迪总统献唱生日歌
I don't know.
不知道
Moustache.
小胡子
这个是在模仿喜剧大师卓别林
No.
不知道
吉恩·凯利在1952年上映的经典电影《雨中曲》中的歌舞表演
Gene Kelly?
吉恩·凯利
Good.
答对了
Your turn now.
轮到你了
Okay, pilgrim.
好了 你们这些旅客
Clint Eastwood?
克林特·伊斯特伍德
克林特·伊斯特伍德 硬汉明星 被称为"城市牛仔"
I don't know. I give up.
我不知道 我放弃
约翰·韦恩：著名的好莱坞西部片明星
John Wayne.
约翰·韦恩
I was just about to say that.
我刚刚想说
I swear. It's amazing.Leon, really brilliant.
我发誓 太神奇了 里昂 你扮得太像了
Amazing
太棒了
You love your plant, don't you?
你很喜欢你的盆栽 对吗
It's my best friend.
它是我最好的朋友
Always happy. No questions.
永远快乐 无忧无虑
It's like me, you see.No roots.
就像我一样 没有根
If you really love it, you should plant it
如果你真喜欢它 就应该把它
in a park so it can have roots.
种在公园里 让它落地生根
Leon
里昂
You should be watering me if you want me to grow.
同样你想让我长大 也该为我浇水
You're right.
没错
They gotta be jumping out of the plate. They gotta be alive.
它们要能从盘子里跳出来 要够新鲜
It's been a long time, Leon.
好久不见 里昂
I missed you.
我想你了
And you missed some nice jobs too.
你也错过了一些好工作
Been training.
我在训练
Training's good, but don't overdo it.
训练是好事 但别过头了
Training don't pay as good as working, Leon.
工作可比训练赚得多 里昂
Tony...
托尼
all the money I make, that you keep for me...
我赚的那些钱 你帮我保管的钱
You need some money?
你需要用钱吗
Just curious.
我就是问一下
I've been working a long time...
我为你工作这么久
and I haven't done anything with my money.
从来没用过那些钱
I thought maybe someday
我想也许有一天
I could use it.
我会用到它
You met a woman.
你有女人了吗
You gotta be careful with women.
你要小心女人
Remember when you arrived in this country?
记得你刚来这个国家的时候吗
When I took you in,
我收留你的时候
you were still wet behind the fuckin' ears...
你还是个毛头小子
and, already, you were in deep shit because of a woman.
却已经因为女人趟进了浑水
Don't forget that, Leon.
别忘了 里昂
I wish I could sometimes.
有时我真希望我能忘了
You know, about my money...
你知道 我的钱
Maybe I could give a little
也许我可以分一点
to someone.
给别人
You know, to help out.
去帮助别人
It's your money. I'm just holding it for you, like a bank.
这是你的钱 我只是替你保管 像银行一样
Except better than a bank
但我比银行好
because banks always get knocked off.
银行经常会被抢劫
No one knocks off old Tony.
没人抢得了老托尼
Besides, with a bank...
此外 把钱存进银行
there's always tons of forms and all that shit.
有成吨的狗屁表格要填
But old Tony, nothin' to read,
在我这儿 不用看
nothin' to write.
不用写
It's all in his head.
都在我脑子里
I know how to read now.
现在我能识字了
That's good, Leon, good.
那很好 里昂 很好
Your money's here. Whenever you want it,
你的钱在这儿 你需要
you just ask me.Here's a grand.
就来问我拿 这里有一千元
- Come on. - It's okay. I don't need it.
- 拿着 - 没事 我不需要
Take it. Have some fun. Go ahead.
拿去吧 找点乐子 拿着
Thank you.
谢谢
All right.
好了
Now let's talk business.Don't move.
现在我们来谈谈生意 别走
I'll go get the file.
我去拿资料
Manolo, a glass of milk for my friend Leon here.
马诺洛 给我朋友里昂来杯牛奶
Listen, Mathilda, you better be careful.
听着 玛蒂尔达 你最好小心点
You can't just speak to any guy off the street.
不要随便跟街上的陌生人讲话
Leon, get a grip. What's the big fucking deal?
里昂 紧张什么 这他妈有什么大不了的
I was just smoking a butt while I was waiting.
我只是在等你的时候 借根烟抽抽
I want you to stop cursing.
我不许你讲脏话
You can't talk to people like that all the time.
你不能总这样和别人交谈
I want you to make an effort to talk nice.
我要你学着好好讲话
And I want you to stop smoking. It will kill you.
还有 我希望你把烟戒了 这会要了你的命的
Okay
好的
Stay away from him. He looks like a weirdo.
离他远一点 他不像好人
Okay
好的
I'll be out in five minutes. Stand where I can see you.
我五分钟后出来 站在我能看见你的地方
Okay
好的
Leon, I think I'm kinda falling in love with you.
里昂 我好像有点爱上你了
It's the first time for me, you know.
我第一次有这种感觉
How do you know it's love if you've never been in love before?
你从没谈过恋爱 你怎么知道这就是爱
Cause I feel it.
因为我感觉到了
Where?
哪儿
In my stomach.
在我的胃里
It's all warm.
暖暖的
I always had a knot there, and now it's gone.
我以前老是胃疼 现在不会了
Mathilda, I'm glad you don't have a stomachache anymore.
玛蒂尔达 我很高兴你的胃病好了
I don't think it means anything.
但这不能说明什么
I'm late for work. I hate being late for work.
我要迟到了 我最讨厌迟到了
Hey, How's the practicing going?
嗨 小提琴练得怎么样了
How are we today, miss?
今天怎么样 小姐
A little sick of practicing.
我有点厌倦练琴了
I understand.
我懂
But you're doing all right.
但是你做得很好
I haven't received any complaints.
没有人来投诉你们
I put a cloth over the strings to lessen the noise.
我在弦上放了块布来减少噪音
That's very smart.
真聪明
Not everyone loves music.
不是人人都爱音乐的
I know.
我知道
What exactly does your father do?
你父亲到底是做什么的
He's a composer.
他是作曲家
That's wonderful.
真厉害
Except he's not really my father.
不过他其实不是我父亲
He's my lover.
他是我爱人
Think I'll go for a walk.
我要去散步了
What are you doing Saturday night?
周六晚上你有事吗
What about dinner?
一起吃晚餐怎么样
Where you goin'?
你要去哪里
Visiting friends at 6J.
拜访6楼J室的朋友
Go ahead.
去吧
We know you're a busy man.
我们知道你是个大忙人
We'll make this short.
我们也想快点完事
If you'll just take us step-by-step
你一步一步说清楚
through exactly what happened.
这里到底发生了什么
The guy was here. He went for his gun.
那家伙在这儿 他要去拿他的枪
Bang, we shot him.
砰的一声 我们打中了他
Where exactly were the kids?
孩子们当时在哪里
I don't know!
我哪知道
They should have been at school, don't you think?
你不觉得他们当时应该在学校么
Your statement said you were the first man in.
你的陈述里面说你是第一个进入屋子的人
Didn't you see any kids?
难道你没看见孩子么
The door was broken. What happened?
大门也坏了 发生了什么
Did you follow the procedure?
你是按程序来的么
I lost a good man here.
我失去了一个好队员
What the fuck do you want with me?
你他妈的到底想让我怎么样
Cooperation.
配合
I haven't got time for this Mickey Mouse bullshit!
我没时间在这里跟你们扯淡
You want cooperation? Come up in my office, room 4602.
你想让我配合你工作 来我办公室 4602
Kids should be at school.
孩子就应该去上学
Come on, that's my ball!
拜托 那是我的球
Give that back. Where you goin'?
还给我 你去哪儿
Damn! Where you goin', man? That's my ball!
该死 你干什么 那是我的球
Follow the blue car.
跟着那辆蓝色的车
You want me to blast the music and go through the lights?
你是让我在鸣警笛的车面前闯红灯么
No, drive slowly.
不 慢慢开
Take the hundred bucks, and shut the fuck up.
拿着这一百块 他妈的给我闭嘴
I do not want to fight you, but you leave me no choice.
我不想和你打 但我别无选择
Boy, you just gave me a great idea!
好孩子 你提醒了我
I mean a big one!
这办法太好了
Welcome back to E! News Daily...
欢迎回到E频道 现在是每日新闻
our 30-minute look at the latest in entertainment news.
现在让我们用30分钟的时间回顾一下娱乐大事件
I'm Bianca Ferrar.
我是碧昂卡·费拉尔
It's for you. A present.
这是给你的 一份礼物
Do you want me to open it? I'll open it.
想打开么 我来开
How do you like it? Nice, eh?
怎么样 喜欢么
Mr. McGuffin?
麦高芬先生
Can I have a word with you?
我能跟你谈谈么
Here. It's for a contract. Twenty grand, right?
这个是合同 两万
His name is Norman Stansfield, and he's in room 4602...
他叫诺曼·史丹菲尔德 他住在4602
in the D.E.A. Building, 26 Federal Plaza.
联邦广场26号缉毒大楼4602
I'm not taking it.
我不收
Why not?
为什么
It's too heavy. Well.
钱太多了
Will you rent me your gear for the day?
你的枪能租给我用一天吗
I never lend out my gear.
我的枪从不外租
But you still have your gun. Use it.
但你不是有自己的枪么 用那个
Just do me a favor. Don't shoot out the window.
帮我个忙 别打碎玻璃
Why are you so mean to me?
你对我怎么这么吝啬
Wildly killing people you don't give a shit about...
你随便杀一些毫不在意的人
but you won't get the bastards that killed my whole family?
但就是不帮我解决那些杀了我全家的人
Revenge is not good once you're done.
一旦开始复仇 就不会有好结果的
Believe. It's better to forget.
相信我 还是忘了好
Forget? After I've seen the outline
忘了 在我看到地板上
of my brother's body on the floor...
我弟弟尸体的轮廓之后
you expect me to forget?
你竟然想让我全都忘了
I want to kill those sons of bitches.
我要杀了那些狗杂种们
Blow their fucking heads off.
爆他们的头
Nothing's the same
在你杀了人之后
after you've killed someone.
一切都会不一样
Your life is changed forever.
你的人生会被完全改变
You have to sleep with one eye open for the rest of your life.
你的余生恐怕都得睁一只眼闭一只眼睡觉了
I don't give a shit about sleeping, Leon.
我他妈才不在意怎么睡觉 里昂
I want love or death.
我要爱 或死
That's it.
就这样
I want death.
我选择死亡
Get off my case, Mathilda. I'm tired of your games.
玛蒂尔达 放过我吧 我对你的游戏已经感到厌倦了
There's this really great game, Leon.
这是个很棒的游戏 里昂
Makes people nicer. Starts them thinking.
让人变得聪明 学会思考
The kind of game you love.
你喜欢的那种游戏
If I win you keep me with you for life.
如果我赢了 你一辈子都不能离开我
And if you lose?
如果你输了呢
Go shopping alone, like before.
你就可以像以前一样自己去买东西
You're gonna lose, Mathilda.
玛蒂尔达 你一定会输的
There's a round in the chamber. I heard it.
子弹上膛了 我听出来的
So what?
那又怎样
What's it to you if I end up with a bullet in the head?
要是我在你面前被子弹爆了头 会怎样
Nothing.
不会怎样
I hope you're not lying, Leon.
里昂 我希望你说的是实话
I really hope that deep down inside there's no love in you.
我真的希望 在你内心深处对我没有一丝的爱
Because if there is just a little bit of love in there for me...
因为只要在你心里 对我有一丝的爱
I think that in a few
几分钟之后
minutes you'll regret you never said anything.
你就会后悔没有阻止我
I love you, Leon.
我爱你 里昂
I win.
我赢了
I took a hit. I need a hand now.
我受伤了 需要一个帮手
I know she's young, but she learns fast.
我知道你担心她太年轻 但是她学得很快
Kids need to be shaped into something, right?
学习要从娃娃抓起 不是么
I know. I taught you that.
我知道 这是我教你的
But ain't there an age limit?
但我们不是有年龄限制么
She's 18.
她18岁了
Really?
真的么
How about something to drink, Tony?
托尼 来点喝的吧
Sure. Manolo, glass of milk for Leon.
当然 马诺洛 给里昂来杯牛奶
Nice tattoo.
很棒的刺青
Manolo, make that two.
马诺洛 来两杯
What's that for?
那是干嘛的
Can't afford to catch cold.
感冒了可不好
First you find out where the chain is.
首先 你得先找到门链子
You can't see it, but you can feel it. Here.
你看不着 但用手能摸出来
I'll ring, you start talking.
我一按门铃 你就说话
What do I say?
我要说什么
Whatever you want.
什么都行
Yes?
谁啊
It's Susan.
我 苏珊
I'm sorry. You must have the wrong door, little girl.
不好意思 你走错了 小姑娘
I don't know any Susan.
我不认识一个叫苏珊的
Move back a little. I can't see anything.
你往后站 我看不见
The light's out. It's all dark out here.
灯坏了 这里很黑
Mister, I'm scared.
先生 我好害怕
Okay.
好啦好啦
What the fuck are you doing?
你他妈在干嘛
Open up.
张嘴
If it leaves your mouth, I'll pull the trigger, capisce?
枪管离开你的嘴我就扣下扳机 明白吗
Here's okay. Let it go. I said, "Let it go."
对 就这样 松开 我让你松开
Move. Move over.
去 去那边
Easy. Easy.
放松 别激动
Go ahead. Your turn.
去吧 该你了
Help me. Please don't beat me.
救命 求你别打我
Sir?
先生
Sir, it's not my dope.
先生 那不是我的毒品
Sir, look l...
先生 看
A little left, please. Sir, look l...
请往左边站点好么
Now, the security shot.
为了保险起见
No, the second goes higher on the chest.
不 第二枪要打在胸部上方一点
Aim for the heart and lungs.
瞄准心脏和肺
There. Right there. You see?
这儿 看到了么
The first shot takes him out of order.
第一枪让他倒地
The second finishes him off.
第二枪让他归西
Never in the face.
千万别打脸
If they can't recognize the client, you don't get paid.
雇主认不出他要杀的人 不会付钱的
You could take out anybody and said you did the job.
因为你可以随便杀一个人交差
Got it?
懂了么
Got it. Never in the face.
懂了 不打脸
Now you can put the tools away.
你现在可以把工具收起来了
What the fuck is going on? Hey, mister!
到底怎么回事 先生
What are you fuckin...
草 到底怎么回事
You see, when you use the silencer a lot...
你看 当你消音器用得太久的时候
you have to put a piece of cloth here...
你要在这儿垫块布
because it gets very hot and could burn it inside.
因为它会发热 然后里面烧起来
Okay
好的
A damp, black cloth is the best.
最好用一块黑色的湿布
What you doing?
你干什么
We said no women, no kids.
我们说过不杀女人和小孩儿
Who do you think this is gonna kill, junkies and monkeys?
你知道这些毒品会害了谁吗 并不是那些混混 地痞
Now it's clean.
这样就干净了
Let's get out of here.
走吧
I thought we don't have the right to drink.
我还以为我们没权利喝酒呢
I know, but we're making an exception for your first time.
是 但是今天为你第一次干活破一次例
Well, if we're making exceptions for a job well-done...
既然我们可以为工作成果而破例
how about a kiss, like in the movies?
那不如像电影一样 轻轻吻一下
No.
不可以
Yes.
可以
What you doing?
你要干嘛
I'm going to kiss you.
我要亲你
I want you to stop, please.
不要这样 不要
Come on. Just a kiss.
来吧 就亲一下
Stop. Everyone is watching us. Go sit down.
快停下来 大家都看着呢 去坐好
Enjoy.
慢用
You don't believe me, do you?
你不相信我 对吧
How's that?
为什么这么说
When I say I'm in love with you.
当我说我爱上你了的时候
Mathilda, please drop it. Just change the subject, okay?
玛蒂尔达 别说了 我们换个话题好吗
Okay. Okay. Sorry.
好 好 抱歉
So, how old were you when you made your first hit?
那 你第一次杀人的时候多大
Nineteen.
十九岁
Beat you.
比你早哦
What you doing?
你在做什么
Can't afford to catch a cold.
感冒了可不好
There's no doorbell.
这儿没门铃
So knock on the door.
那就敲门
Yes?
谁
Hi. I'm looking for Mr. Reuben's apartment...
你好 我是来拜访鲁宾先生的…
but it's all dark out here in the hall, and I'm lost.
但是走廊里好黑 而且我迷路了
Just a second.
等一下
You want more? Come on. Show your fucking face.
还想要么 来吧 把你的脸露出来
You think you're going to get me that easily?
你们觉得那么简单就能杀了我吗
When it's tough like this, you know it's gonna be ugly.
遇到这样强硬的对手时 场面肯定不好看
Better make it quick or
最好快点解决他
else we'll be all day listening to his crap.
不然我们就要一直听他废话
Asshole! Come on, show me your fucking face, faggot!
混蛋 来吧 让我看看你的脸 娘娘腔
Come on, gum trick.
再来一个口香糖的把戏啊
Hey,What about the ring trick? You know that one?
嘿 你知道拉环把戏么
Ring trick? Come on, asshole. I'm waiting.
拉环把戏吗 来啊混蛋 我等着呢
Show it to me, motherfucker.
给我看看啊 混账东西
That's the ring trick.
这就是拉环把戏[手榴弹]
Mario, go back to the barbershop. We'll finish later.
马里奥 你先回理发店吧 我们一会儿再剪
Hey Leon, what's up?
里昂 你好啊
All done already?
都解决了吗
No.
没呢
Nicer than people, eh?
这东西比人好啊
I told you that.
以前就告诉过你
You got a problem?
你遇到麻烦了吗
No.
没有
Get the chair. Sit down.
拿把椅子来 坐吧
I was thinking.
我最近在想
If something happens to me someday...
如果哪天我遇到不测
Hey, Leon, nothing's gonna happen to you.
里昂 你不会遇到不测的
You're indestructible. Bullets slide off you.
你这么无坚不摧 子弹遇见你都会绕道
You play with 'em.
这些对你来说都是小意思
Tony, I thought about my money.
托尼 我考虑了如何处理我的钱
You remember the girl who came here the other day?
你记得前几天来这儿的女孩么
Yes.
嗯
Her name is Mathilda.
她的名字是玛蒂尔达
If anything happens to me...
如果我遭遇不测
I'd like you to give her...
我希望你能把我的钱
my money.
给她
You can count on me, Leon.
这事包在我身上 里昂
Thank you, Tony.
谢谢你 托尼
I won't be long.
我很快就回来
Did I do something wrong?
我犯错了吗
No. This one is too big.
没有 这一单太大了
Yeah, and I only get the leftovers, is that it?
是啊 我只能挑你剩下的做 是这样吗
Mathilda, since I met you everything's been different.
玛蒂尔达 我遇见你之后 所有事情都不同了
So I just need some time alone.
所以我就是想独处一会儿
You need some time to grow up a little.
你需要一些时间成长
I finished growing up, Leon. I just get older.
我已经够成熟了 里昂 我只会变老
For me it's the opposite. I'm old enough.
我正好相反 我已经够老了
I need time to grow up.
但我还不够成熟
Shit.
妈的
Come on! Hustle!
快 投篮
- Good shot. - Come on.
- 好球 - 过来
You're new, aren't you? Fifth floor, right?
你刚搬过来对吧 住在五楼是吗
You can't sit here like that.
你不可以直接坐这儿
Really, why not?
是吗 为什么
Nothing's free. Like a parking meter.
这不是免费的 就像停车要收费
When you stop, you pay.
你停这儿 就要付钱
It's the law.
这是规矩
Only on T.V.
电视里才这样
What do you say?
你说什么
Forget it. How much is your meter?
没什么 你要多少钱
Ten dollars a month.
十美元 每月
Got change?
有钱找么
Don't worry about it. We'll do ten for twelve.
算了 我一次性给你十个月的钱
I'll pay now for the rest of the year.
就算我付了一年的钱
Okay, a year.
好的 一年
Does paying rent here mean
是不是我付了钱
- I have to put up with you guys? - Er, no.
- 还得忍受你们 - 额 不是
So go play somewhere else.
那就哪儿凉快哪儿呆着去吧
I need to think.
我需要思考
Stand up. Don't you like your job?
站直点 你是不是不想要你的工作了
Food.
吃的
Where you going?
你去哪里
Special delivery, room 4602.
快递 4602房间
Sign here.
在这签字
Have a nice weekend, girls.
周末愉快 姑娘们
Special delivery? Let me guess.
快递是吧 让我猜猜
Chinese?
中国菜
Thai, maybe?
或者 泰国菜
I've got it. Italian food.
我知道了 意大利菜
What's your name, angel?
你叫什么名字 宝贝儿
Mathilda.
玛蒂尔达
I want you to put the sack on the floor.
把这袋东西放地上
Good.
很好
Now I want you to tell me
现在我希望你告诉我
everything you know about Italian food.
你对"意大利菜"的了解
Don't forget the name of the chef who fixed it for me.
别忘了告诉我 那个让你来的厨师的名字
Nobody sent me. I do business for myself.
没人叫我过来 是我自己要解决问题
So this is something personal, is it?
所以这是个人恩怨 对吗
What filthy piece of shit did I do now?
我他妈又做什么了
You killed my brother.
你杀了我弟弟
I'm sorry.
对不起
- And you wanna join him? - No.
- 你想和他一起吗 - 不
It's always the same thing.
人们都一样
It's when you start to become really afraid of death...
当你开始由衷地恐惧死亡时
that you learn to appreciate life.
才开始学会珍惜生活
- Do you like life, sweetheart? - Yes.
- 你热爱生活么 宝贝 - 是的
That's good.
很好
Because I take no pleasure
因为我不喜欢
in taking a life
杀死一个
if it's from a person who doesn't care about it.
不热爱生命的人
Stan,
史丹
I've been looking all over for you. I checked upstairs...
我刚刚到处找你 楼上找遍了
What? I'm busy.
怎么了 我现在很忙
It's Malky, man. He's dead.
是马尔奇 他死了
Malky was makin' a buy for us from the Chinaman.
马尔奇当时在中国人那里帮我们买东西
But they got nothin' to do with it.
但他们与这件事无关
They told me this guy came from the outside.
他们告诉我杀手从外面进来
He was a pro.He was fast. He fuckin' came out of nowhere.
是个职业杀手 动作麻利 不知道从哪里冒出来
Boom, shoots the Chinaman dead in two seconds.
砰 击毙了那个中国人
Easy, man. I'm a cop.
别激动 我是警察
Then turns around, says something to Malky like...
然后他转身 对马尔奇说
No women, no kids.
不杀女人和小孩儿
I think it was somethin' personal.
我觉得这是个人恩怨
Death is
今天的死神
whimsical today.
让人捉摸不透
Blood,
布拉德
do you hear me?
你在听我说吗
Yeah, I hear you, Stan. Just chill out, man.
是的 我听着呢 史丹 别激动
Would you take her up to my office?
你能把她带到我的办公室吗
All right, yeah.
可以
Jesus fucking Christ.
我滴个上帝啊
"Leon, my love.
"亲爱的里昂
I know where to find the guys who killed my brother.
我找到杀死我弟弟的人了
Their boss is Norman Stansfield.
他们的上司是诺曼·史丹菲尔德
He's in the D.E.A. Building, room 4602.
他在联邦大楼 4602号房间
I'm gonna do them myself. If something goes wrong,
我要亲手杀了他 如果我出了什么意外
I left you 20 grand on the table.
我在桌上给你留了两万块
It's for a contract. Five grand a head, right?
合同规定好的 五千块换一个人头 对吗
I know I'll feel better after I do this.
只有杀了他我才能安心
I love you. Mathilda.
我爱你 玛蒂尔达
Wait for me. I won't be long.
在这儿等我 我去去就来
I can't park in front like this. It's a federal building!
我不能停在这里 这是联邦大楼
He's gonna do the same exact thing that I said.
他会按我说的做
A nine "Millie".
一把九厘米手枪
Bullets.Another nine "Millie".
子弹 又一把九厘米手枪
What'd you plan to do with all these guns?
你带着这些枪是要干嘛
Maybe she was planning on taking out the whole building.
她也许是想拿下整栋楼呢
Holy shit! What we got here? Lunch.
天啊 看这是什么 中饭
Careful, Blood, might be poisoned.
小心点 布拉德 可能有毒
1991年 加州发生食用鳀鱼 导致海鸟死亡的多莫酸中毒事件
No,man.There's no anchovies on this.
不会的 上面又没有鳀鱼
Is that what you call 'I won't be long'?
这就是你所谓的"去去就来"
I been hanging around here for at least ten minutes.
我在这儿晃了至少有十分钟
I did my best.
我尽快了 走吧
Do you like it?
你喜欢吗
Yes.
嗯
So say it.
那就说出来
I like it.
我喜欢
Not thirsty?
不渴吗
You know, a girl's first time is very important.
你知道吗 女孩的第一次非常重要
It determines the rest of her life sexually.
这决定了她之后的生活是否性福
I read that once in one of my sister's magazines.
我在姐姐的杂志上看到的
My girlfriends told me they hated their first experience.
我闺蜜告诉我 她们的第一次并不美好
That's because they didn't love the guys.
因为她们不爱那些男的
They just did it to show off.
她们那么做只是为了以后炫耀
Afterwards, they started liking it, like cigarettes.
但后来 她们开始享受了 感觉就像抽烟一样
Will I like it the first time?
我的第一次会是美好的吗
Mathilda, no.
玛蒂尔达 不行
Why not?
为什么不行
I just can't.
我就是做不到
You love someone else?
你爱着别人吗
No.I mean...
不 我的意思是
There was someone a long time ago.
很久之前 在我还没来美国的时候
Before I came to the States.
我爱过一个人
Her father didn't want her to see me.
她爸爸不希望她和我联系
She was from a very respectable family.
她出身名门望族
Mine was...
而我家却
you know...
你懂的
not so respectable.
没什么名望
Her dad went nuts every time she'd take off to see me.
每次她出来见我 她爸爸就会抓狂
She still snuck off to see you, right?
但她仍然偷偷溜出来见你 对吧
Right.
对
See, nothing can stop love, Leon.
你看 爱是不可阻挡的 里昂
He killed her.
他杀了她
One shot through the head.
对着她头部开了一枪
They kept him in jail for two days, and they let him go free.
他只在监狱待了两天 就被放出来了
They said it was an accident.
他们说那是场意外
So...
所以
one night I waited for him.
有天晚上 我潜伏着
Five hundred feet with a lens.
在五百英尺外 用一支狙击枪
He also had an accident.
也让他发生了意外
The same night I took a boat and came here...
当天晚上 我坐船到了这里
to meet up with my father who was working for Tony.
来投奔我的爸爸 他当时在为托尼工作
I was 19.
我那时十九岁
Since then I've never left the city, and...
从那以后 我就再没离开过这座城市
I've never had another girlfriend.
也没再谈过恋爱
You see, Mathilda...
你懂了吧 玛蒂尔达
I wouldn't be a good lover.
我不会是个好恋人
Okay.
好吧
Would you do me one favor?
你可以答应我一件事吗
What?
什么
I'm sick of watching you sleep on your chair.
我不想再看到你在椅子上睡觉了
We're gonna share the bed.
我们同床睡吧
I don't think it's a good idea.
我觉得这样不好
It's okay.Put your legs up on the bed.
就这样 把腿放到床上
Yeah. That's nice.
不错 非常好
Put your head down. It's okay. Relax.
躺好 就这样 放松点
Good night, Leon.
晚安 里昂
Good night.
晚安
Manolo, take the kids in the kitchen.
马诺洛 把孩子们带进厨房
I have a lot of respect for your business, Tony.
我很尊重你的事业 托尼
When you've killed for us in the past...
你以前帮我们杀人的时候
we've always been satisfied.
从没让我们失望过
That's exactly why today
正因为如此
is going to be very hard for me.
今天我非常为难
I hope you'll excuse my mood.
希望你能体谅我的情绪
My man was killed right here on your turf.
我的人就在你的地盘上被杀了
The Chinks tell me that the hit man...
中国佬告诉我
was kind of the Italian type.
杀手有点像意大利人
So we figured that Tony might know something.
所以我们想 托尼也许知道些什么
Wait.
等等
There's more.You're gonna love this.
听我说完 还有更精彩的呢
A few hours later, a little 12-year-old girl
几小时之后 一个十二岁的小女孩
comes into my office armed to the teeth,
全副武装地 闯进我办公的地方
with the firm intention
铁了心地
of sending me straight to the morgue.
要把我送进太平间
Do you know who came and got her in the middle of the afternnon right there
你知道下午从我的地盘上把她救出去的人
in my building?
是谁吗
The very same Italian hit man.
就是那个意大利杀手
I'm dying to meet him.
我特别想会一会他
Relax. Everything's fine.
别紧张 一切正常
Sleep well?
睡得好吗
I never really sleep.
我从没真正睡着过
Got one eye open always.
一直不敢睡得太熟
Yeah, I forgot.
是哦 我忘了
I never saw someone
我可从没见过谁
with one eye open snore so much.
睡得不熟 呼噜还能打得这么响
I snore?
我打呼了？
Like a baby.
像个婴儿一样
I'm gonna get some milk for breakfast. I won't be long.
我去买些牛奶当早餐 很快就回来
Don't forget the code when you come back.
回来时别忘了暗号
Two knocks, then one, and two knocks again. Right?
两下 一下 然后再两下 对吧
Right.
对
Hello, Signore. Ring these up. I'm gonna go get some milk.
先生您好 算算这些多少钱 我去拿点牛奶
From here on out, you don't make a sound.
从现在起不许出声
You answer my questions by nodding yes
你需要回答我的问题
or shaking your head no. You got it?
点头肯定 摇头否定 明白了吗
Is he alone?
他只有一个人吗
Does he expect you?
他在等你吗
Do you have keys to the apartment?
你有房间的钥匙吗
Is there a code, a way of knocking, so he knows it's you?
你们之间有识别身份的敲门暗号吗
Alpha team.
阿尔法队
Final position. We're ready to go.
已就位 准备就绪
Be careful.
小心点
Move! Move!
退后 退后
Shit.
该死
Alpha team. Man down. Man down.
阿尔法队 人员伤亡 人员伤亡
I told you.
我提醒过你了
Benny.
本尼
Bring me everyone.
把所有人都找来
What do you mean, "Everyone"?
所有人是什么意思
Everyone!
每 一 个
Take this.
拿着这个
Go take a look.
去看一眼
Don't move.
别动
Do you see anything?
你看见什么了
It's the guy.
是他
He's here. He's got a gun to my head.
他就在这儿 拿枪指着我的头
Ok. Nobody moves.
知道了 大家都别动
Let the girl go.
把那女孩放了
Take it easy, man!
兄弟 冷静点
Let the girl go.
把那女孩放了
Okay, the girl's comin' out.
好的 我们放她走
Let the girl go.
把这女孩放了
Grab the axe off the wall. Over there. Go!
把斧子从墙上取下来 在那儿 快去
You're coming with us.
你得跟我们走
Christ, he shot him!
天哪 他冲他开枪了
Bastard!
混蛋
Move! Move! Move! Move!
闪 闪 闪 闪
Shut the fucking water off!
去把这该死的水关了
Got it.
明白
Come
过来
We're in a bad way here.
我们处于劣势
Send the cats.I repeat,sent the cats.
派人进来 再说一遍 派人进来
I don't know what happened.
我不知道是怎么回事
I didn't see 'em coming, I swear!
我没看到他们进来 我发誓
I just went shopping
我只是去买东西
and I came back, and they were everywhere.
回来的时候 他们就把楼封锁了
Stay away from the window.
不要靠近窗户
Leon.
里昂
Come here.
过来
Snipers.
是狙击手
Okay, now, get this fucking asshole out of there.
现在 把那个混蛋给我抓出来
How are we gonna get outta here now?
我们要怎么出去
Leave it to me. We're checking out.
交给我吧 是时候退房了
But Leon it's not big enough for you.
但是里昂 这儿对你来说太窄了
It's barely big enough for me.
只能勉强够我钻进去
We said no discussion.
说好了都听我的
No, I'm not letting...
不 我不会抛下
I'm not going! I won't go!
我不走 我绝对不走
Listen to me.
听我说
We have no chance together.
我们一起的话 没有逃生的可能
But if I'm alone, I can do it.
但如果我单独行动 就能逃掉
Trust me. I'm in good shape, Mathilda.
相信我 我很强的 玛蒂尔达
I know I've got a lot of money with Tony, a lot.
我在托尼那儿存了一大笔钱 一大笔
We'll take it and leave together,
我们带上那笔钱一起远走高飞
just the two of us.Okay? Go.
就我们两个人 好吗 快走
No! You're saying that so I won't worry.
不要 你只是在安慰我而已
I don't wanna lose you, Leon.
我不想失去你 里昂
You're not gonna lose me, Mathilda.
你不会失去我的 玛蒂尔达
You've given me a taste for life.
你让我体会到生命的真谛
I wanna be happy, sleep in a bed, have roots.
我想要做快乐的人 睡在床上 落地生根
You'll never be alone again.
我不会再让你孤身一人
Please, go now, baby. Go.
求你了 快走吧 宝贝儿 快走
Calm down. Go now. Go.
冷静点 快离开这儿 去吧
See you at Tony's. I'm gonna clean them all.
我们在托尼那儿见 我会把他们全部杀掉
Tony's in an hour.
一小时后托尼那儿见
I love you, Mathilda.
我爱你 玛蒂尔达
I love you, too, Leon.
我也爱你 里昂
Hey, what the fuck is going on up there?
喂 楼上他妈的在干什么
I just said "Take the guy out", not the fucking building.
我只说要抓住那个男的 不是让你们拆了这栋操蛋的楼
We've got one breathing here!
这儿还有一个活人
Get a medic on the horn!
快叫医生
We've got a wounded man. Make way!
这里有一个伤员 让一下
Down those stairs.
把他送下楼
Let's go! Move!
下来 快点
Get that guy off the stairs! Lay him on the layer.
把伤员送下楼 放在担架上
Get your team back out there!
让你的人退到那儿去
We've got two men comin' down the stairs. Let's hurry!
有两名队员要下楼 抓紧时间
You okay? Hey, I need a medic over here!
你还好吗 嘿 这里需要一个医生
Move your fuckin' asses.
快滚过去
Squad Number One, what's the status on the apartment?
第一小队 房间里现在是什么情况
Can't see shit. Too much smoke.
烟太浓了 屁都看不见
Give us five minutes.
再给我们五分钟
Okay. You got it.
好的 去吧
What? Two hundred men
什么 两百个大汉
can't find one man and a girl? Did you find the girl?
还找不到一个男人和一个小女孩吗 找到小女孩了吗
Hi, how are you doing? Take your mask off, quick.
嗨 感觉怎么样 把你的面罩摘下来 快
Let me see you. That's deep. Right. And this one here...
让我检查一下你的伤口 很深啊 好 再检查一下这里的伤口
You're from the 3rd Precinct?
你是第三警区来的吗
Let's open up his sleeve a little bit.
来把他的袖子稍微弄开一点
All right, fine. Put it down. This one.
没事了 放下吧 换这只手
You stay there for two minutes. I'll be right back.
在这儿等两分钟 我马上回来
Let me put the mask back on. I breathe better with it.
让我把面罩带上 这样呼吸更顺畅一点
OK. You're all right. Sit tight.
好的 你不会有事的 坐着别动
Come on, everybody out!
快点 所有人都出去
Let's go! Out!
走走走 都出去
Clear the way, men.
哥们 给他让条道
What are you doing here? Get out. Come on.
你在这儿干什么呢 赶紧离开 快
Stansfield?
史丹菲尔德吗
At your service.
静候差遣
This is from...
这个是
Mathilda.
替玛蒂尔达给的
Shit.
妈的
Leon asked me to help you out if somethin' happened,
里昂说 如果出事了就让我帮你一把
and I think somethin' happened, right?
我想应该是出事了 对吧
He put aside a little cash for you.
他为你留了点钱
So what I'm suggesting is that...
我是这么想的
seein' as how you're still so young...
你还这么年轻
I should hold the money for you until you're older.
所以在你长大之前 就由我来替你保管这笔钱吧
Like a bank, you know, except...
你懂的 就像银行一样 只不过
it's better than a bank 'cause banks always get knocked off.
我这儿比银行更保险 因为银行总会破产
No one knocks off old Tony.
而老托尼始终屹立不倒
But it's your money. In the meantime...
不过这毕竟是你的钱 在这期间
all you gotta do is come here every once in a while...
你只需要隔三差五来这儿一次
and I'll dish it out so you can have a little fun, OK?
从我这儿取点钱去找乐子 好吗
Here's a hundred bucks to start.
开始就先给你一百块吧
Can't I get a job instead?
我不能在这儿工作吗
A job?
你说工作
What the hell can you do?
你又能做些什么鬼
I can clean.
我会杀人
I ain't got no work for a 12-year-old kid...
我这儿可没有能让十二岁小孩做的工作
so get it out of your goddamn head!
别再有这样该死的想法了
It's over! The game's over!Leon's dead!
都结束了 游戏结束了 里昂死了
You hear me?
听懂了没
Come on. You think I ain't hurtin' too?
好了 你觉得我就不难过吗
But he's dead.
但是他已经死了
You're gonna forget all this craziness
你得把这些破事儿都忘了
and get your little ass back to school, capito?
然后好好滚回学校念书 懂了吗
Now take this money and get the hell outta here.
现在拿上这些钱 快滚吧
Don't let me see your face till next month...
这个月内别让我再看到你的脸
'cause something tells me
因为我感觉
I'm about to lose my famous kind streak.
我一直以来的好脾气就快崩不住了
My parents...
我的父母
died in a car accident four weeks ago.
四周前在车祸中丧生
It was terrible.
那太可怕了
We didn't have the time
在你第一次来这儿的时候
to get to know one another when you first came here...
我们没有时间互相了解
but I want you to know
但我希望你能明白
I'm not the kind of woman who'd let down a child...
我绝不会让一个孩子感到失望
whatever her situation, whatever her mistake.
不管她的处境如何 也不管她犯了什么错误
So I'm going to help you
所以我会帮助你
and do my best to welcome you here again.
也真心实意地欢迎你回到这里
But on one condition:
但是我有一个条件
You have to stop lying to me, Mathilda.
你必须告诉我实话 玛蒂尔达
I want you to take a chance and trust me.
我希望你能试着相信我
Now tell me what happened to you.
现在告诉我到底发生了什么事
Okay.
好吧
My family got shot down by D.E.A. Officers...
我的家人因为毒品纠纷
because of a drug problem.
被缉毒组的警察开枪打死了
I left with the greatest guy on Earth.
一个世界上最好的男人带我逃走了
He was a hit man, the best in town,
他是一个职业杀手 在镇上首屈一指
but he died this morning.
但是今天早上他死了
If you don't help me,
如果你不帮我的话
I'll be dead by tonight.
可能我今晚就会死掉
You know her?
你们认识她吗
I've never seen her.
从来没见过
I think we'll be okay here.Leon.
我想我们能在这儿安心生活了 里昂
片尾曲：《Shape Of My Heart》
∮He deals the cards as a meditation And those he plays never suspect∮
他玩牌的样子似在冥想 从未有人怀疑他的智商
∮He doesn't play for the money he wins He doesn't play for respect∮
他并非要赢得金钱 也不是为了人们的敬赏
∮He deals the cards to find the answer The sacred geometry of chance∮
他只想找到一个答案 那神秘的几何概率
∮The hidden law of a probable outcome The numbers lead a dance∮
那无法预料的结果 各种法则在数字下隐藏
∮I know that the spades are the swords of a soldier∮
我知道黑桃代表卫兵的剑
∮I know that the clubs are weapons of war∮
我知道梅花是战争的炮枪
∮I know that diamonds mean money for this art∮
我知道钻石象征着财富
∮But that's not the shape of my heart∮
但是我的红心 我的心它没有形状
∮He may play the jack of diamonds He may lay the queen of spades∮
他可以打出钻石王子 他可以打出黑桃皇后
∮He may conceal a king in his hand While the memory of it fades∮
他可以隐藏手中那张国王 而那些回忆逐渐的逐渐的消亡
∮I know that the spades are the swords of a soldier∮
我知道黑桃代表卫兵的剑
∮I know that the clubs are weapons of war∮
我知道梅花是战争的炮枪
∮I know that diamonds mean money for this art∮
我知道钻石象征着财富
∮That's not the shape of my heart∮
但是那并非我心的形状
并非我心的形状
∮And if I told you that I loved you∮
如果我告诉你我爱你
∮You'd maybe think there's something wrong∮
你也许会觉得不适应吧
∮I'm not a man of too many faces The mask I wear is one∮
我并非多重性格的男子 我所有的只是这一副面具
∮Those who speak know nothing And find out to their cost∮
妄言的人无知 他们为此付出了代价
∮Like those who curse their luck in too many places∮
好像那些反复诅咒自己命运的人
∮And those who fear are lost∮
他们脸上失去了阳光
∮I know that the spades are the swords of a soldier∮
我知道黑桃代表卫兵的剑
∮I know that the clubs are weapons of war∮
我知道梅花是战争的炮枪
∮I know that diamonds mean money for this art∮
我知道钻石象征着财富
∮But that's not the shape of my heart∮
但是那并非我心的形状
∮That's not the shape of my heart∮
并非我心的形状